[Music]
[âm nhạc]
On May 18th, Year of the Rabbit, Ms.
ngày 18 tháng 5 năm Quý Mão Vừa qua cô
Pham Thi Yen, along with representatives of the
chủ nhiệm Phạm Thị Yến cùng đại diện các
Buddhist practitioners from the Golden Chrysanthemum Club practicing the
phật tử trong câu lạc bộ Cúc Vàng tập tu
Six Harmonies, were present at Minh Dao Pagoda in
Lục Hòa đã có mặt tại chùa Minh Đạo
Ho Chi Minh City to offer alms to the
thành phố Hồ Chí Minh để cúng dường Chư
monks during the 2023 summer retreat. With
tăng nhân mùa an cư kiết hạ năm 2023 với
a fervent desire for the merits from the
lòng khát ngưỡng công đức từ sự tu tập
pure practice of the monks, Ms. Pham Thi Yen,
Thanh Tịnh Của Chư tăng cô Phạm Thị Yến
representing the Buddhist practitioners of the
đã đại diện cho các phật tử trong câu
Golden Chrysanthemum Club, offered donations of money and
lạc bộ cúc vàng Dương cúng Tịnh tài và
goods totaling
vật phẩm cúng dường với tổng trị giá là
120 million VND to commemorate the merits of the
120 triệu đồng để tôi hỉ công đức tu tập
three-month summer retreat of the Venerable monks
trong 3 tháng an cư của chư tôn Đức tăng
and practitioners. We humbly pray that the Venerable Abbot
và hành giả an cư ngưỡng Mong trên Hòa
and all the venerable monks will mercifully accept our merits, so that we may continue to
thượng cùng chư tôn thiền đức từ bi hoan
benefit from their virtues, so that the
hỷ lạc thọ cho chúng con được ăn mày
Buddha's teachings may flourish, and all sentient beings may be imbued with the
công đức của quý ngài chúng con lại hiện
Buddha's teachings, deeply believe in karma, and attain
được thấm nhuần lời Đức Phật dạy tin sâu
liberation through virtuous conduct. We
nhân quả hướng thiện tâm giải thoát
also pray that the Venerable monks may enjoy peace of mind, their
chúng con cũng mong nguyện chư tôn thiền
wisdom may shine brightly, and their
Đức được pháp thể khinh An Tuệ đang
Buddhist endeavors may be accomplished, serving as a
Thường Chiếu Phật sự viên Thành làm ngọn
guiding light for us.
đuốc ánh sáng dẫn đường cho chúng con
Namo Buddha Shakyamuni.
Nam Mô Phật Bổn Sư Thích Ca Mâu Ni
Before the sincere devotion of the
trước lòng thành kính của các phật tử
Buddhist followers, Venerable Thich Thien Nhan, Chairman of the
hòa thượng Thích Thiện Nhân Chủ tịch Hội
Central Executive Council and Head of the Sangha Affairs Committee of the
đồng trị sự trưởng ban tăng sự Trung
Vietnam Buddhist Association,
ương Giáo hội Phật giáo Việt Nam viện
Abbot of Minh Dao Thien Pagoda,
chủ chùa Minh Đạo Thiên chủ Hạ trường đã
representing the Venerable Monks,
đại diện Chư Tôn Đức tăng từ bi hứa Khả
mercifully accepted the offerings from the Buddhist followers
Thọ nhận sự cúng dường của các phật tử
under the name of the annual summer retreat. This is a
với tên thẳng an cư kiết hạ hàng năm là
fundamental condition for the monks and
điều kiện căn bản của Chư tăng cũng như
all male and female Buddhists, as the ancient masters said, "The practice is
tất cả nam nữ phật tử vì cổ đức đã nói
collective, not just for
là chúng tu chứ không phải riêng như
monks and nuns, but for all male and female Buddhists."
tăng ni không mà gồm cả nam nữ phật tử
Therefore, the practice of the monks and nuns is
cho nên sự tu tập của chư Tăng Chư ni
also the practice of all male and
cũng chính là sự tu tập của tất cả nam
female Buddhists. Because every time the esteemed Buddhists
nữ phật tử vì sao vì mỗi khi quý phật tử
come to the pagoda to make offerings during the summer retreat, they are already
đến chùa cúng dường hội hạ thì đó chính
practicing and cultivating merit
là đã tu hành rồi tu tạo Phước Điền công
for themselves. As the ancient masters
đức đối chính bản thân mình như cổ đức
said, the development of Buddhism depends on the Sangha's
từng nói phật pháp phát triển được là do
propagation of the Dharma, and the flourishing of the Zen school depends on the practice of cultivating the
tăng già Hoằng Hóa Thiền môn Hưng Thịnh
mind. Thus, the
được thì do đàn diệt pháp tâm như vậy sự
generous offerings of all male and female
phát tâm cúng dường của tất cả nam nữ
Buddhists contribute to the development of the
phật tử là chính giúp cho sự phát triển
Sangha's monastic facilities and provide the
cơ sở tự viện của Giáo hội và sự An ổn
monks with the necessary conditions for their studies and practice
đầy đủ điều kiện cho Chư tăng tu học
during the three months.  The practice of residing in the summer retreat, as well as
trong 3 tháng an cư kiết hạ cũng như các
subsequent periods, is an extremely
thời gian sau đó là một công đức vô cùng
great meritorious deed, a testament to the Buddha's teachings. Therefore,
lớn lao mà được đức Phật Ấn ký vì vậy
ancient masters have emphasized that
cho nên cổ Đức cũng từng quấn thị rằng
to reach liberation, one should
muốn lên bờ giải thoát thì dùng thiền bố
first practice meditation and generosity; to cultivate merit,
thí làm đầu muốn tu tạo Phước Điền thì
offering to the Sangha is paramount. Thus, by
cúng dường Chư tăng là trên hết do đó
cultivating the Bodhi Mind and offering pure wealth and material possessions
cho nên cứ tự đã Phát Tâm Bồ Đề Dân phẩm
to the Sangha
vật Tịnh tài đến Cúng dường Chư tăng
during this summer retreat, one is
trong mùa an cư kiết hạ này chính là tu
cultivating merit towards the Three Jewels (Buddha, Dharma, and Sangha). The merit of this
tạo Phước Điền đối với ngôi Tam bảo pháp
merit
tăng và theo thành tựu công đức Phước
resides in the heart of every
Điền ở tại nơi chính tâm của mọi người
Buddhist follower. Of the three meritorious fields,
phật tử về vì trong ba thứ Phước Điền
Buddhist followers have clearly seen the field of reverence (the Buddha), the field of gratitude (
quý phật tử cũng từng thấy rõ kính Điền
parents' gratitude), the field of purity (the Sangha),
cha mẹ và thanh tịnh Điền tức là chúng
and the field of compassion (
tăng và bi Điền Tức là tất cả chúng sinh
all sentient beings). These are the four meritorious fields that all
đây là bốn Phước Điền mà tất cả những
Buddhist followers must understand and
người con Phật đều phải thấy rõ và tu
practice. Constantly paying homage to the Buddha is the
hành thường đảnh lễ Phật Kính Phật đó là
sowing of the seed of merit; the field of reverence is
gieo giống Phước Điền với phật bảo thì
the second, the field of purity; the field of
tĩnh điện thứ hai đi Điền Ân Điền tức là
gratitude (parents' gratitude) is the meritorious deed, which must be acknowledged and
công ơn cha mẹ phải biết và cố gắng lo
repaid. The
đền đáp công ơn của cha mẹ thành tựu
third meritorious field is the field of gratitude.  The Pure Field is where
Phước Điền thứ hai đó là ân Điền thứ ba
all monks diligently practice and
là thanh tịnh Điền đó là tất cả Chư tăng
uphold the three unlearned precepts of morality, concentration, and
tu hành tinh tấn giữ gìn ba môn vô học
wisdom for three months,
Giới Định tuệ trong 3 tháng nạp với Đức
accumulating merit and
ăn thêm thành tựu được phước đức và
wisdom through virtuous actions. These are the
thành tựu được Trí Huệ Đây là những điều
conditions to fulfill the aspirations and
kiện để mà đáp ứng yêu cầu mong mỏi và
offerings of all benefactors and royal
sự cúng dường của tất cả đàn Na thí chủ
benefactors present here.
trong các vương tử đang hiện đây đó là
The
thanh tịnh điện như thì gieo cái ống
Pure Field is where the seeds of merit are sown, and on this basis, the
Phước Điền trên cơ sở này thành tựu được
merit is clearly achieved. There is nothing
công đức rất rõ ràng không Cái gì sai
different. Finally, there is the Field of Compassion, which means all
khác cuối cùng là bi Điền Tức là tất cả
sentient beings
chúng sinh
demonstrate compassion and relief from suffering through Buddhist teachings,
thể hiện đến thời từ bi cứu khổ đạo Phật
bringing peace and happiness to each person. This is the field of merit, sowing charity,
đem về an vui mỗi người vân vân Taiwan
social work, helping the poor, and assisting those in need.
tác xã hội cứu giúp cho người nghèo khó
Wherever there are disasters or floods,
nơi nào xảy ra tai nạn lũ lụt làm công
charitable work, building houses,
tác từ thiện xây dựng nhà cửa làm đầu
roads, and providing
làm đường xây dựng nhà thì nghĩa tình
medicine is done with compassion and kindness. This
thương bố thí thuốc men gã vân vân Đây
is the field of merit. By
là thuốc diệt công đức Phi Điền gieo
cultivating this merit, all sentient beings
trồng công đức này đối Tất cả chúng sinh
achieve the Field of Compassion. These are the
như vậy thì thành tựu được bi Điền đó là
four fields of merit that the Buddha taught, and
bốn thứ Phước Điền mà Đức Phật đã dạy
today, Buddhists have
rồi cho ngày hôm nay phật tử đã thực
correctly followed the Buddha's teachings.
hiện đúng theo lời dạy của đức Phật có
During
nguyệt vị tổ sư nhân mùa an cư kiết hạ
this year's Rains Retreat (Buddhist calendar 2567), we, the devout
phật lịch 2567 năm nay đến đây quý phật
Buddhists, have been guided by Venerable Truc
tử đã được hướng dẫn của Thượng Tọa Trúc
Thai Minh, the abbot of Ba Vang Pagoda (also known as
Thái Minh là trụ trì chùa Ba Vàng Tức là
Bao Quang Tu Pagoda), who traveled from Quang
bảo Quang Tự trường xá xa xôi từ Quảng
Ninh to here. We, along with some Buddhists from
Ninh vào đây cũng như một số Phật tử tại
Ho Chi Minh City, have also visited the
thành phố Hồ Chí Minh đã vấn đề Tịnh
Pure Land Dharma Assembly of Minh Dao Pagoda to
Nghiệp Hiệp Đạo tràng chùa minh đạo để
offer prayers and make offerings to the Ten Directions of Buddhas
thuyết lễ nên cúng dường Mười Phương Chư
and the Venerable Monks. This brings immense merit, which we, the devout Buddhists, understand correctly according to the teachings of the Buddhas and Patriarchs. We respectfully, on
Phật và Chư tổ chúng tôi xin được mạn
behalf of all the venerable monks and
phép thay mặt cho toàn thể chư đại đức
practitioners of the Rains Retreat at
tăng hành gia an cư tà nghiệp đạo tràng
Minh Dao Pagoda, joyfully and sincerely
chùa Minh Đạo hoan hỷ và thành tâm tiếp
accept these offerings. We, the Buddhists, are
nhận lễ phẩm cúng dường phật tử chúng
extremely happy to be able to rely
con vô cùng hạnh phúc khi được nương tựa
on the Three Jewels and make offerings to the Three Jewels to
vào tam bảo được cúng dường tam bảo để
gain blessings for
lấy phước lành cho Phật tử tại gia của
our lay followers. Today, we have the
chúng con mà hôm nay chúng con được hy
rare opportunity to be guided
hữu nhân duyên được hòa thượng chỉ dạy
by the Venerable Abbot on the duties of lay practitioners. We
cho con bổn phận của người cư sĩ tại gia
promise before the Venerable Abbot that
chúng con xin hứa trước hòa thượng chúng
we will diligently encourage each other to practice
con sẽ chăm chỉ sách tấn nhau thực hành
these four types of meritorious deeds so that
bốn loại Phước Điền này để đời này chúng
we may be happy in this life and in the next.  We, your children, are filled with
con được hạnh phúc đời sau chúng con
joy and we respectfully wish the Venerable Abbot
được an vui chúng con kính chúc trên Hòa
abundant health and a
được thật nhiều sức khỏe trụ thế sa Bà
long life in this world, so that
thật là dài lâu để cho hàng phật tử
we Buddhist followers may have a place to take refuge. We
chúng con có nơi chốn nương tựa chúng
also respectfully wish all the Venerable Monks and Masters good health and protection
cũng luôn luôn được mạnh khỏe che chở
for us Buddhist followers on the path to
cho Phật tử chúng con trên con đường
enlightenment. We also vow that from
giác ngộ chúng con cũng xin nguyện từ
this life to countless lives to come, we will always take
đời này cho đến vô lượng đời sau cũng
refuge in the Three Jewels as the Venerable Abbot has promised. With utmost sincerity,
được nương tựa vào tam bảo như lời bị
we respectfully bow in gratitude to the Venerable Abbot
tổn hòa thượng chúng con chi tiết Chí
and all the Venerable Monks and Masters. Namo Buddha
cùng chư tôn thiền Đức Nam Mô Phật Bổn
Shakyamuni.
Sư Thích Ca Mâu
Truly, we also pray that the
thực sự cũng dừng này nguyện mong Chư
monks will diligently practice and cultivate merit
tăng an cư tu hành tinh tấn làm Phước
for humanity and the heavens, and dedicate our prayers for the flourishing of
Điền cho nhân thiên và Hồi Hướng Nguyện
Buddhism, for the
Cầu mong cho Phật pháp được Thịnh Hưng
Three Jewels to remain in the world, for peace and prosperity in the land, and for
tam bảo thường trú ở thế gian đất nước
the people to be happy and peaceful.
Thái Bình nhân dân Hòa Lạc
[Music]
[âm nhạc]